Pratik Joglekar

Senior Product Designer

Philadelphia, US • <u>letstalk@pratikjoglekar.com</u> • + 1 (267) 504-9700 • <u>LinkedIn</u> • <u>Personal Website</u>

SUMMARY

I am a product designer with over five years of experience in design, possessing a growth mindset and a comprehensive skill set encompassing research through design implementation. In practice, I am a passionate designer at heart and an eloquent and motivated design leader.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

HubSpot

Senior Product Designer

September 2022 - Present

- Owned a cross-team collaboration and provided guidance to ensure a successful introduction to a new tool on the pricing page web page from research to design, and maintained synergy between teams.
- Achieved a 4% improvement in monthly recurring revenue by effectively promoting a pricing strategy for a product.
- Created a comprehensive strategy from discovery to design by identifying trade-offs and adopted quickly in an ambiguous situation to create a new pricing page bundle promotion.
- Planned a design sprint session and multiple workshops to foster brainstorming new ideas for end-to-end user flow improvements.
- Collaborated and drove discussions with multiple designers to architect a cohesive ecosystem by creating a design brief for a new product and created user experiences by ensuring consistency with existing designs.
- Analyzed qualitative and quantitative data by conducting experiments to implement design improvements.
- Created a service blueprint to help identify business and user problems for product usage and experimentation tools by collaborating with the project manager, engineers, analyst, and content designer to strategically prioritize the implementation roadmap for design.

MassMutual

Senior Product Designer

January 2020 - August 2022

- Championed and communicated design initiatives within the organization, advocating for the importance of design within the company.
- Organized multiple R&D teams that included junior designers, project managers, and engineers by providing guidance and fostering a cohesive approach to design.
- Led to build a mobile design system for iOS and Android and spearheaded the entire design process for mobile app by ensuring strategic objectives.
- Invented and developed a visual QA guide for consistent design implementation.
- Instigated the design effort for a new product offering from research to design and extended support for UX writing in an agile environment.
- Advocated for qualitative and quantitative research within the team and fostered a research-first approach.

Teltech Systems

Product Designer

February 2019 - November 2019

• Instrumented design effort for mobile app by ensuring consistent user experience, resulting in a user-friendly mobile app.

Fortune Cookie UX Design

Product Designer Consultant

March 2017 - July 2017

Created a medical application with gamification to enhance educational content for medical students.

EDUCATION

Thomas Jefferson University

Philadelphia, US

Master of Science in User Experience and Interaction Design

2017-2018

MENTOR AND JURY MEMBER

ADPList and Mento Mentor

 Created a psychologically safe space for designers by providing mentorship and fostering professional guidance, feedback, and collaborative design experience.

Publications

• Published various Medium and Smashing Magazine articles on UX Planet and Bootcamp from UX Collective.

Jury member

• Thomas Jefferson University invited me multiple times to be a Jury member for the UX design program's thesis defense.

SKILLS

Communication • Critical Thinking • Collaboration/Teamwork • Problem solving • Receptive to feedback • Adaptability • Empathy • Time management • Attention to details • Flexibility • Growth mindset • Design thinking • Strategic thinking • User research - qualitative & quantitative • System design • Information architecture • Usability testing • Prototyping • Visual design • UI design • Product design • Web and mobile design - iOS and Android • Wireframe • Customer journey map • Figma • Sketch • Invision